A Finding Aid to the Guy Dill Papers, 1972-2003, in the Archives of American Art AAA.dillguyp
Archives of American Art
Guy Dill papers
1972-2003
AAA.dillguyp
Archives of American Art
1.3 Linear feet
The papers of sculptor Guy Dill measure 1.3 linear feet and date from 1972-2003. The collection includes a few scattered personal and business letters, writings, photographs of artwork, two project files, and printed material, including exhibition announcements, brochures and catalogs of solo and of group shows, newspaper and magazine articles.
Dill, Guy, 1946-
Scope and Contents note
The papers of sculptor Guy Dill measure 1.3 linear feet and date from 1972-2003. The collection includes a few scattered personal and business letters, writings, photographs of artwork, two project files, and printed material, including exhibition announcements, brochures and catalogs of solo and of group shows, newspaper and magazine articles.
Biographical/Historical note
California sculptor Guy Dill (1946-) is known for his large-scale, muscular works in both traditional and modern materials. He was born in Jacksonville, Florida, in 1946 and raised in Southern California. After receiving a BFA with honors from Chouinard Art Institute in Los Angeles in 1970, Dill exhibited his works widely, earning an international reputation for his multipartite constructions executed in aluminum, steel, formed concrete, glass, bronze, marble, and wood. His sculptures range from classically poised geometric structures to asymmetric constructions.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers were donated by Guy Dill in 2004.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged in five series.
Series 1: Letters, circa 1989-2003 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 2: Writings, 1977-1979 (Box 1; 1 folder)
Series 3: Photographs, 1969-2003 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 4: Projects, 1981-1982, circa 1991 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1989-2003 (Box 1-2; 1.0 linear foot)
Related Archival Materials note
Within the Archives holdings is an oral history interview of Guy Dill conducted by Paul Karlstrom in 2000. The interview transcript is available on the Archives of American Art website.
Photographs; Sculptors--California--Venice
- Letters, circa 1989-2003; Series 1; 2 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains business letters in regard to artwork commissioned by L’Ermitage Hotels, a forthcoming exhibit at Meyerovich Gallery, and a letter of appreciation from the International Sculpture Center; personal letters and cards from friends, including Don Bachardy, Susan Factor, and Richand L. Weisman.
  - Personal Letters, circa 1989-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Business Letters, 1989-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Writings, 1977-1979; Series 2; 1 Folders Box 1
  This series contains hand-written notes and photo-copied lecture notes for Dill’s Sculpture class at UCLA.
  - Teaching Notes for Sculpture Class, UCLA, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Photographs, 1969-2003; Series 3; 2 Folders Box 1
  This series contains black and white and color digital photographs of Dill’s artworks.
  - Photographs of Artwork, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Artwork, 1987-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Projects, 1981-1982; circa 1991; Series 4; 2 Folders Box 1
  This series contains a press release for Lexington Hills Estates Sculpture Commission, and a voice-over script, photo-copied story board, insurance form, and payment break-down for a Sanka Brand Decaffeinated Coffee television commercial.
  - Lexington Hills Estate Sculpture Commission, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sanka, TV Commercial, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Printed Material, 1989-2003; Series 5; 1 Linear feet Box 1-2
  This series includes auction catalogs, exhibition catalogs for solo and group shows; exhibition announcements, including PACE Gallery, Wenger Gallery, Annex Gallery, Chac Mool Gallery, and Meyervich Gallery; an Alumni Exhibition at Roberts Art Gallery/Santa Monica High School, with artists: Lita Albuquerque, Laddie John Dill, and Guy Dill; dedication of Jonathan Borofsky’s, Ballerina Clown and Dill’s, Harmonic Arch (1989); an invitation to a fund-raiser for U.S. Senator, Barbara Boxer at Dill’s studio (1992); magazine and newspaper clippings; a date-book, Art in Venice; and magazines.
  - Auction Catalogs, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, solo, undated; 1972-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, group, undated; 1971-1997 (Box 1, Folder 14-30)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Bobbie Greenfield Gallery, 1997-2003 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1974-2001 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Date book, Art in Venice, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Journal, ZYZZYVA, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1974-2001 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Magazine Clippings, undated; 1981-2001 (Box 1, Folder 36-40)
  - Oversized Publications, 1985-2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)